Contact

Gouda, The Netherlands +31 657552871 (Mobile) kiffin.gish@planet.nl

www.linkedin.com/in/kiffin (LinkedIn) github.com/kgish (Other)

Top Skills

Scrum

Agile Methodologies
Software Development

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
French (Limited Working)
Dutch (Full Professional)

Certifications

Unit Testing in Angular
The Data Scientist's Toolbox
Advanced Typescript
Certified Scrum Master
Angular Architectures for Enterprise
Applications

Kiffin Gish

Angular and Ruby on Rails (freelance)
Gouda

Summary

Advanced software development of web-based applications and platforms using modern frameworks for tooling and testing.

Passion to facilitate good software development processes, coach and inspire teams to build great platforms that they can be proud of.

Both front- and back-end expertise, including JavaScript, Angular 11, RxJS, NgRx, Nrwl/Nx, Material Design, Bootstrap, Ionic, NodeJS and Express, Nestjs, HTML, CSS, Ruby on Rails, Docker, Microservices.

Guided by a balanced mix of structured Agile/Scrum methodologies and plain old "hands-on-roll-up-your-sleeves" mindset to get the job done.

Experience

Gishtech

Full Stack Developer April 2016 - Present (5 years 2 months) Rotterdam Area, Netherlands

I build slick web-based applications and platforms using modern JavaScript, Node and Ruby on Rails. Professional consultancy on advanced software development, methodologies, tooling, people and processes. Pure front-and backend development from user stories and software programming, through testing, deployment and after-care. HTML, CSS, JavaScript (Angular, TypeScript, jQuery, Ember, Node and Express), Ruby on Rails, Rust, C/C++ and Perl. Linux, Apache and MySQL. Agile, Scrum or just plain hands-on roll up your sleeves and get the job done.

Alii Senior Frontend Developer June 2020 - May 2021 (1 year) Utrecht, Netherlands Modern web-based platform to create better medical protocols and guidelines for specialists in the health care industry, based on latest research data.

JavaScript, Angular 11, HTML, CSS, RxJS, NgRx, Nrwl/Nx, Ionic, Bootstrap, Sass and UX Design. Selenium, WebdriverIO, Jasmine, Mocha and Cypress.

Vereniging COIN
Full Stack Developer
December 2017 - November 2019 (2 years)
Gouda. Netherlands

Design and implementation of an inhouse telecom cloud platform providing API services to Dutch operators. Technologies include JavaScript, Angular, Material Design, RxJS, Java, Kotlin and AWS. Emphasis on frontend development, but also did backend and devops work. All development based on agile and scrum methodologies. Recruited, coached and helped build a solid development team from scratch.

Blokker Holding Release Manager ICT May 2015 - November 2015 (7 months) Amsterdam Area, Netherlands

Defined and tracked process for delivering quality products according to deadlines. Worked closely with Nextail in planning of product roll-outs that was essential in meeting high expectations in the retail segment. The E-commerce backend was based on IBM WebSphere which provided a unified platform for store chains falling under Blokker Holding (Blokeer, Xenos, Intertoys, Leen Bakker, Bart Smit and Marskramer).

Zarafa

Development and Release Manager January 2014 - January 2015 (1 year 1 month) Delft Area. Netherlands

I was responsible for the development, quality assurance and release management of all of the Zarafa open source email and collaboration software products. The ZCP platform provided an advanced middleware solution based on Linux as a viable replacement for MS-Exchange. Introduced a more agile software development process pipeline based on Scrum and Continuous Delivery. Web-based client was a single-page ExtJS application using a bespoke PHP/MAPI protocol. Teams were located in Holland, India, Germany and Brazil, along with International partners and customers. Man

management, monthly one-on-ones, job evaluations, coaching and training. Relevant languages: C/C++, Python and MVC JavaScript.

Sdu Information Solutions
Manager Development
December 2011 - January 2014 (2 years 2 months)
Amsterdam Area, Netherlands

Built up a software development factory to support a product suite of advanced web-based content platforms for government, municipalities and provinces. Involved with streamlining the software development processes, as well as the overall process improvement for supporting other departments and external technology partners. Provided second line support to the help-desk with maintenance and trouble-shooting, functional and technical application issues. Built from scratch a new professional software development environment based on agile and Scrum. Relevant languages: Java, JEE, JavaScript, PHP, Ruby on Rails.

Nokia (Navteq)
Development Team Manager / Lead Engineer
December 2010 - July 2011 (8 months)
Frankfurt Area, Germany

Responsible for the search and geocoding development team which designed, built and deployed an advanced web-based map services platform (JEE and C/C++) for international customers wanting to leverage their presence in the location based services (LBS) arena. Ramped up an international team of software developers using Agile and Scrum, continuous delivery and test driven development, a key focus of mine being man management and personal/agile coaching.

Interapy BV Head of ICT April 2009 - November 2010 (1 year 8 months) Amsterdam Area, Netherlands

Responsible for infrastructure, maintenance and support, and new development activities. Migrated legacy systems to a modern high available hosted infrastructure. Web-based computer mediated therapy via the Internet using the Perl web framework called Catalyst, JavaScript (jQuery). Worked closely with expert psychologists in designing and implementing the next generation flag ship therapy product. Designing, implementing online

screening surveys and scoring methods/models for treatment protocols, using OO-Perl and Template::Toolkit and open source tools.

TomTom International BV
Team Leader Software Development
May 2007 - April 2009 (2 years)
Amsterdam Area, Netherlands

Responsible for a team of top-notch software engineers designing, developing and rolling out a robust and highly scalable LBS (location based services) platform. In addition to providing geocoding, mapping, HD traffic, travel advisor and POI capabilities, we built a web-based route planner for showcasing the extensive TomTom product portfolio on the company web site (routes.tomtom.com), which received very positive reviews worldwide. Based on agile software development (Scrum), using JEE, Spring, JBoss, GridGain, C/C++, Perl, Apache, JavaScript, Ajax and JSON. Did man management, recruitment and bi-yearly reviews. Created from scratch and instructed inhouse Scrum trainings for developers and project leaders.

Previous experience
Team Lead, Software Developer, System Engineer ...
March 1988 - April 2006 (18 years 2 months)
Netherlands and UK

More details concerning my previous work experience, skills and various functions, as well as references can be provided upon request.

Education

Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam

Drs., Physics / Computer Science · (1983 - 1988)

Stanford University
Bachelor of Science - BS · (1975 - 1979)

Salinas High School High School, Honors · (1971 - 1975)